Hey. Don't we have any more booze?
Il n'y a plus d'alcool ?
It's my painkiller.
C'est mon antidouleur.
Damn.
Mince.
Aren't we there yet?
C'est encore loin ?
That place where they're supposed to give us the money.
Là où ils doivent nous donner l'argent.
Don't be in such a hurry. We're almost there.
Ne sois pas si pressé. On y est presque.
The Troll's Son
Le fils du Troll
Damn.
Mince.
Damn it.
Bon sang.
-My whole body hurts. -I want to find me a nice girl.
- Mon corps souffre. - Je veux rencontrer une fille sympa.
ENGLAND VICINITY OF HUMBER RIVER
ANGLETERRE ENVIRONS DU HUMBER
Who's going to watch the ships?
Qui va surveiller les navires ?
We're just here to rest our bones.
On est ici pour se reposer un peu.
We're not going to stay here for long.
On ne reste pas longtemps.
Get up.
Levez-vous.
Hey. Don't run away. I'll kill you if you move.
Ne courez pas, ou je vous tue.
Don't let anyone get away. We're going to have trouble if this gets out.
Ne laissez personne s'en tirer. On aura des problèmes, si ça s'ébruite.
Two on the right.
Deux à droite.
And then the guy ate it. He didn't even know what it was.
Puis le type l'a mangé. Il ne savait même pas ce que c'était.
-My head hurts. -I drank too much.
- J'ai mal à la tête. - J'ai trop bu.
What happened? Did you have a hard time falling asleep?
Que s'est-il passé ? Du mal à t'endormir ?
There was a noisy little fly in my room.
Il y avait un insecte bruyant dans ma chambre.
A little fly?
Un insecte ?
Who's that? A survivor?
Qui est-ce ? Un survivant ?
No. It's the son. The Troll of Jom's kid.
Non. C'est le fils. Celui du Troll de Jom.
He's still alive?
Il est encore vivant ?
Too much trouble for the early morning.
Il est trop tôt le matin, pour ces ennuis.
This is revenge for my father.
Je vais venger mon père.
I challenge you to a duel.
Je te défie en duel.
Impressive, kid.
Impressionnant petit.
I'm so scared.
J'ai vraiment peur.
What are you going to do, Askeladd?
Que vas-tu faire, Askeladd ?
What a pain.
Quel ennui.
Come on.
Allons.
You should have cut off my head while I was asleep.
Tu aurais dû me couper la tête, pendant mon sommeil.
I'm the son of Thors.
Je suis le fils de Thors.
I'd never do something
Je ne ferais jamais rien
so cowardly.
d'aussi lâche.
Wow, I'm so scared.
J'ai peur.
-Did you hear that, Askeladd? -Kill him, kid.
- Tu as entendu, Askeladd ? - Tue-le, petit.
Get him.
Vas-y.
So, you think you're a warrior?
Tu penses être un guerrier ?
All right. Come at me.
D'accord. Viens te battre.
Yeah. Just like that.
Oui. Comme ça.
Someone dig him a grave.
Que quelqu'un creuse sa tombe.
Damn. Damn.
Zut.
You can't let your sword swing you around like that.
Tu ne peux pas te laisser balader par ton épée.
You're so brutal.
Tu es brutal.
Maybe he's dead already.
Il est peut-être déjà mort.
Come on.
Allez.
We confirmed it.
C'est confirmé.
Here's your money.
Ton argent.
Thank you very much.
Merci beaucoup.
Say thanks to Floki for me.
Remerciez Floki pour moi.
I can't get too friendly with the villagers.
Je ne peux pas être trop gentil avec les villageois.
By the way, I have a message for you.
Au fait, j'ai un message pour toi.
A message?
Un message ?
"How was Thors's final moment?"
"Comment a été le dernier moment de Thors ?"
It was nothing special.
Rien de spécial.
He just died a normal death.
Il est mort normalement.
What? You're still alive?
Quoi ? Tu es vivant ?
You look terrible.
Tu as mauvaise mine.
Want some?
Tu en veux ?
It's not healthy to deprive yourself.
Ce n'est pas sain de te priver.
What's wrong with him?
Qu'est-ce qu'il a ?
We were only trying to help.
On essaye juste d'aider.
Damn.
Mince.
Damn it.
Bon sang.
He died an honorable death.
Il est mort honorablement.
Thors sacrificed himself for us.
Thors s'est sacrifié pour nous.
I'm sorry, Helga. Ylva.
Je suis désolé, Helga. Ylva.
My words cannot express how sorry I am.
Je ne peux exprimer à quel point je suis désolé.
He's already dead. No one can do anything about it now.
Il est mort. Personne n'y peut rien.
Crying about it will just make you hungry.
Pleurer vous affamera.
Time to get back to work.
Au travail.
Helga.
Helga.
Thorfinn...
Thorfinn...
I'm going to find him, no matter what.
Je vais le trouver, quoi qu'il en coûte.
No matter how many years it takes.
Peu importe le nombre d'années que ça prendra.
Well, I never thought he'd live a long life anyway.
Je n'ai jamais pensé qu'il vivrait longtemps.
It's hard having a strange dad like him.
C'est difficile d'avoir un père comme lui.
Your little brother is missing, too, right?
Ton petit frère a disparu aussi, non ?
Are you okay, Ylva?
Ylva, ça va ?
I'm so busy, now that the men are all gone.
Je suis très occupée, depuis que les hommes sont partis.
Ylva.
Ylva.
Yeah.
Oui.
You're crazy, Ylva.
Tu es folle, Ylva.
Mother, how are you feeling?
Mère, comment te sens-tu ?
Yes. I feel much better.
Je me sens mieux.
Sorry to rely so much on you, Ylva--
Désolée de dépendre de toi, Ylva...
Okay, okay.
Ça va.
It's okay. Don't get up.
C'est bon. Ne te lève pas.
Oops, I forgot about the sheep.
J'ai oublié le bétail.
Okay, okay. Sorry I'm late.
Excusez-moi, je suis en retard.
I must shear the sheep when spring comes too.
Je dois tondre les moutons, à l'arrivée du printemps.
Yeah.
Oui.
I got the first hit.
La première prise est pour moi.
I'm so busy.
Je suis débordée.
We don't have enough people to pitch in.
Nous n'avons pas assez de monde.
Maybe I should get a husband.
Je devrais peut-être me trouver un mari.
Thanks.
Merci.
Let's go to sleep.
Allons dormir.
You can go to sleep first.
Tu peux aller te coucher.
I'm going to finish this.
Je vais terminer.
But it's dark already.
Il fait déjà sombre.
You'll make a mistake.
Tu vas te tromper.
Ylva.
Ylva.
That's enough.
C'est assez.
Get some rest.
Repose-toi.
But I'm almost done.
J'ai presque fini.
I'm okay. I'm not tired.
Je ne suis pas fatiguée.
I'm going to kill him.
Je vais le tuer.
I'm going to kill him, no matter what.
Je vais le tuer, quoi qu'il m'en coûte.
Hey.
Hé.
You're working hard.
Tu travailles dur.
You.
Toi.
How is it?
Comment ça va ?
Have you gotten used to using a sword?
Tu t'es habitué à l'épée ?
You. It's your fault.
Toi. C'est de ta faute.
You used me as a shield.
Tu m'as utilisé comme bouclier.
That's why my father...
C'est pour ça que mon père...
You coward.
Lâche !
Your father really was strong.
Ton père était très fort.
But he was naive.
Mais il était naïf.
That's all there is to it.
C'est tout.
Don't make fun of my father!
Ne te moque pas de mon père !
Well. You're just weak.
Tu es trop faible.
Hey.
Hé.
I ran into that kid in the forest.
J'ai vu le gosse, dans la forêt.
What? He's still alive?
Quoi ? Il est toujours vivant ?
The blood of the Troll of Jom runs through his veins.
Le sang du Troll de Jom coule dans ses veines.
He's not going to die that easily.
Il ne mourra pas si facilement.
Like father, like son.
Tel père, tel fils.
You can't let your sword swing you around like that.
Tu ne peux pas laisser ton épée te balader comme ça.
Damn.
Mince.
We ended up staying here for a long time.
On est resté ici longtemps.
I feel great now.
Je me sens bien, maintenant.
What a comfortable village.
C'est un village confortable.
Someone's coming.
Quelqu'un arrive.
I'm Thors' son, Thorfinn.
Je suis le fils de Thors, Thorfinn.
In the name of Odin, the Almighty,
Au nom d'Odin, le Tout-puissant,
I challenge you to a duel.
je te défie en duel.
Come on. You're so annoying.
Tu es vraiment énervant.
You're pretty brave.
Tu es brave.
Accept the duel, Askeladd.
Accepte le duel, Askeladd.
It's decided, then.
Alors, c'est décidé.
It's the leader's job to meet his men's expectations.
Un chef doit répondre aux attentes de ses hommes.
I, Askeladd, son of Olaf, swear in the name of Odin
Moi, Askeladd, fils d'Olaf, jure au nom d'Odin
that I accept your duel, because I have no choice.
d'accepter ton duel, car je n'ai pas le choix.
Come on.
Allons.
Are you that eager to go meet your father?
Es-tu si pressé de retrouver ton père ?
It's over.
C'est fini.
He can't win.
Il ne peut pas gagner.
Come on.
Allons.
Have you finished?
As-tu terminé ?
How boring.
C'est ennuyeux.
Get up.
Lève-toi.
This is a duel.
C'est un duel.
I think that's enough. He's going to die.
Je crois que ça suffit. Il va mourir.
What's wrong? You're the one who told me to kill him.
Et alors ? C'est toi qui m'as dit de le tuer.
That's it. I've had enough.
Bon, j'en ai assez.
I don't enjoy killing kids.
Je n'aime pas tuer les enfants.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
What do you mean?
Que veux-tu dire ?
I'm busy too.
Je suis occupé.
Wait.
Attends.
I haven't lost.
Je n'ai pas perdu.
Fight. You coward.
Bats-toi. Espèce de lâche.
You're persistent, kid.
Tu es tenace, petit.
It's not over yet.
Ce n'est pas fini,
It's not over until I kill you.
tant que je ne t'ai pas tué.
I swear, I will kill you.
Je le jure, je te tuerai.
Try achieving something great on the battlefield.
Essaye de briller sur le champ de bataille.
You're a Viking, right?
Tu es un Viking, non ?
Then...
Alors...
I'll reward you with a duel.
je te récompenserai avec un duel.
That's a promise?
C'est une promesse ?
Right. A promise between warriors.
Oui. Une promesse entre guerriers.
I'll achieve something in no time.
Je brillerai très bientôt.
And then...
Et alors...
you'll die...
je te tuerai...
by my hands.
de mes mains.